<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>CS Seminars &amp; Educational Trips</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/</link><description>Recent content on CS Seminars &amp; Educational Trips</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:59:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>No Stack to Full Stack</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/no-stack-full-stack/no-stack-full-stack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:59:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/no-stack-full-stack/no-stack-full-stack/</guid><description>Basics of the Web (MySQL) I. Details of the event/activity This webinar was part of a series of webinars entitled No Stack to Full Stack: Basics of the Web. It basically teaches the basics of web development from frontend development to backend development and aims to equip the audience in their full stack journey. This session focuses on the basics of MySQL which is one of the major database systems that are being used.</description></item><item><title>Video Editing 101 with Adobe Premiere</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/video-editing-101/video-editing-101/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 22:50:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/video-editing-101/video-editing-101/</guid><description>I. Details of the event/activity The webinar was organized by my fellow BSCS4 students, and the session focuses mainly on the basics of video editing using Adobe Premiere Pro.
II. Reflections on the seminar/activity gives rise to The session helped me in having a basic idea of editing videos. The speaker explained the concepts in a way that is easily understandable by people who does not have much experience with editing videos.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Microservices</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/demystifying-microservices/demystifying-microservices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 21:32:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/demystifying-microservices/demystifying-microservices/</guid><description>Containerization and Orchestration I. Details of the event/activity The webinar was another event that was held in collaboration with StackLeague and Manulife IT Delivery Center (MITDC) and it mainly focuses on giving an overview of microservices.
As with their previous sessions, they started by introducing the company, MITDC, their company culture and the tech stack that they use. They also had games and gave prizes to the winners which I won as well.</description></item><item><title>StackLeague x MITDC</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/stackleaguexmitdc/stackleagexmitdc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 23:18:17 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/stackleaguexmitdc/stackleagexmitdc/</guid><description>Modern IT Delivery on Cloud I. Details of the event/activity StackLeague x MITDC was an online webinar that was conducted by StackLeague in collaboration with Manulife IT Delivery Center (MITDC) last October 5, 2022. It was a session that focuses on cloud native applications as well as leveraging serverless solutions.
The event started with a brief introduction of MITDC and their culture, what they do as a company, as well as sharing the technology stack that they are using.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Build 2022</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/microsoft-build/microsoft-build-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 17:35:54 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/microsoft-build/microsoft-build-2022/</guid><description>Spotlight on Philippines I. Details of the event/activity The Microsoft Build 2022 is an online/in-person event that was conducted by Microsoft last September 30, 2022. It focuses mainly on the things that Microsoft is currently working on that both developers and anyone who is interested in software might be interested in. This year, the keynote highlights 10 main things namely: Developer flow, Cloud ubiquity, App ubiquity, Cloud-native, Unified data, Models as platforms, Hybrid AI, Low-code/no-code, Collaborative apps and Metaverse.</description></item><item><title>CCS Student Orientation Reflection</title><link>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/orientation/orientation-reflection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 12:46:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jezreal.github.io/seminars-educational-trips/posts/orientation/orientation-reflection/</guid><description>I. Details of the event/activity The student orientation was conducted at the function hall of Gordon College last August 18, 2022 and was conducted by the College of Computer Studies. Although we attended the event face-to-face, it was also streamed live through Zoom and Facebook so that those students that cannot attend will also be able to join the event albeit online.
The event&amp;rsquo;s main objective was to orient the CCS students regarding the policies and guidelines that must be followed by the student specifically in the College of Computer Studies.</description></item></channel></rss>